Dalbir Singh

WEB DEVELOPER - PHP | WordPress | JavaScript



+1-236-987-8514



X dalbirsrana@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/dalbirsrana



github.com/dalbirsrana



🔗 dalbir.me

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, PHP, Node.js

CMS: WordPress, Joomla

Libraries: ReactJS, iQuery

Storage: MySQL

Tools: GitHub, Photoshop

EDUCATION

Post Degree Diploma in Web & Mobile App Development Langara College, Vancouver, BC, Canada 2019 - 2020

Master of Science in Information Technology Panjab University, Chandigarh, INDIA Graduated in 2006

ABOUT ME

Web developer with experience in building high performing, user-friendly responsive websites. Extensive Knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress and RESTful API as well as experience with libraries like ReactJS and jQuery. Up to date on best web practices and agile methodology.

FXPFRIFNCF

- 3 years of full time and 9 years of part time front-end development experience using HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, jQuery and vanilla JavaScript on various platforms likes WordPress, Joomla, NodeJS and Miva Merchant.
- 2 Years of work experience building WordPress themes and plugins with custom functionality.
- 1 year of development experience in PHP framework Codelaniter.
- Experience using version control system Git.

Recent Projects

- http://realistings.wmdd.ca Complete WordPress Site development.
- http://blog.noodor.com WordPress theme development and features integration from scratch.
- https://carbonprint.ca Data visualization website using ReactJS.
- https://smellrid.com eCommerce website theme development and feature integration.
- https://noodor.com eCommerce website theme development from scratch with data import from old store and various other features integration.

Work History

Web Developer - IMTEK Environmental Co, Alpharetta, USA Jan, 2019 to Present – 2 yrs. (Full Time) 2009 to 2018 – 9 yrs. (Part Time)

- Theme Development and feature integration for WordPress and Miva shopping cart from scratch.
- Develop expert solutions with regular website maintenance.
- Website optimization resulting in 70% load time improvement.
- Email template and newsletters development in HTML for campaigns.

Jr. Web Developer - Web Store Engineers, Noida, IND Jan, 2008 to Jun, 2009 – 1.5 yrs.

- WordPress theme development and plugin integration with UI customization.
- Writing, testing and debugging PHP code on frameworks like Codelgniter.

Educator - PGGCG, Sec-11, Chandigarh, IND 2009 to 2019 - 10 yrs.